Guide to the Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet Collection, 1865-1950
- F
  - ________. "The physiology of milk fever I." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1927. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The physiology of milk fever. II." Reprinted from Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, May 1928. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The physiology of milk fever. III. The blood phosphates and calcium" Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1929. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Preliminary observations on bob veal." Annual Report of the State Veterinary College at Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y. (Box 2)
  - ________. "President's address given at the New York State Veterinary Medical Society." Twenty-sixth Annual Meeting, August 3-5, 1915, Ithaca N.Y.. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The rate of passage of material through the digestive tract." Reprinted from The Cornell Veterinarian, April 1923. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Recent progress in our knowledge of milk fever." Reprinted from Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, December 1929. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Seventy years of veterinary service in the United States." Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, May 1929. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Some points on comparative physiology of poultry." Animals, Foods and Diseases, Vol.2, No.1, January 1906. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Some theories and experiments in antisepsis." Presented at the the meeting of the State Veterinary Society in New York, 1898. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The spermatic secretion and its ultraparticles." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, October 1921. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The terminology of the nerve cell." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, September 1984. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The terminology of the nerve cell." Reprinted from Proceedings of Sixth Annual Session of Association of American Anatomists, 1894. (Box 2)
  - ________. "A test for peristaltic activity." Reprinted from theProceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1923. (Box 2)
  - ________. "A test for peristaltic activity." Reprinted from the State Veterinary College Report for the year 1922-1923. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Therapeutic notes from recent Literature." Reprinted from the Report of the Committee on Therapeutics at the meeting of the New York State Veterinary Medical Society, Sept. 1911. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The ultraparticles of the blood and chyle." Reprinted from. (Box 2)
  - ________. "An undescribed constituent of semen." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medecine, 1924. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The use of acetone in histology." Reprinted from the Journal of Applied Microscopy, Vol. II, No.4. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Use of formalin in neurology." Proceedings of the American Microscopial Society, 1895. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The veterinary outlook from a teacher's viewpoint." Reprinted from the Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, July 1922. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The weight curve of castrated kids." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1925, XXII, pp. 248-250. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Why the veterinary profession?." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, Vol. XX, No. 3, July 1930.. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Zoophily versus homophily." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the American Microscopical Society, 1896. (Box 2)
  - Fisher, Irving and Emily F. Robbins. "Memorial relating to the conservation of human life as contemplated by bill (S.1) providing for a United States public-health service." Referred to the committee on public health and national quarantine and ordered to be printed, 5 April 1912. (Box 2)
  - Fitch, C.P. "Organisms morphologically resembling anthrax bacteria." Annual Report of the State Veterinary College, ca. 1905. (Box 2)
  - ________. "A review of the principal methods used to standardize bacterin (bacterial vaccines)." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 13 March 1915. (Box 2)
  - Fleming, William and James N. Neill. "Studies on bacterial enzymes: V. The carbohydrases and lipase of the welch bacillus." Reprinted from the Journal of Experimental Medicine, June 1927. (Box 2)
  - Flexner, Simon and Hideyo Noguchi. "On the plurality of cytolysins in normal blood serum." Reprinted from the University of Pennsylvania Medical Bulletin, July-August 1903. (Box 2)
  - Foote, R.H. and G.W. Salisbury. "The effect of puridium, penicillin, furacin, and phenoxethol upon the livability of spermatozoa and upon the control of bacteria in diluted bull semen." Reprinted from Journal of Diary Science, September 1948. (Box 2)
  - Forbush, William Byron. "Amusement for Convalescent Children." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 19, 1920. (Box 2)
  - Frank, J.F. "The toxic effects of coccidiostatic sulphaonamides in chickens." Reprintd from the Canadian Journal of Comparative Medicine, August and November 1947. (Box 2)
  - Fredericq, Pierre. "Actions antibiotiques réciproques chez les Enterobacteriaceae." University of Liege thesis, 1948. (Box 2)
  - Frei, W. "Vegetatives nervensystem und tierkrankheiten." Reprinted from the Schweizer Archiv fur Neurologie und Pscychiatrie, 1945. (Box 2)
  - __________. "Beziehungen des vegetativen nervensystems zu storungen der fortpflanzung beim weiblichen rind." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Twelfth International Veterinary Congress.1935. (Box 2)
  - __________. Biochemisches und pathologisch-psysiologisches uber rauschbrand-pararauschbrand-impfungen." Reprinted from the Schweizer Archiv fur tierheilkunde, 1942. (Box 2)
  - Freiberg, Joseph A. "Arthritis-the allergic type." Reprinted from American Medicine, October 1930. (Box 2)
  - __________. "The allergic joint." Reprinted from the Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, August 1930. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Allergy as a Factor in the Production of proliferative arthritis." Reprinted from the Archives of Surgery, February 1929. (Box 2)
  - Frey, Carl A. and William A Hagan. "The distribution of acid-fast bacteria in soils." Reprinted from the Journal of Infectious Diseases, December 1931. (Box 2)
  - Frothingham, Langdon. "The history, prevalence and prevention of rabies and its relation to animal experimentation." Defense of Research Pamphlet VII, Council on Defense of Medical Research of the American Medical Association, 1910. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The Rapid Diagnosis of Rabies." Reprinted from The Journal of Medical Research, April 1906. (Box 2)
  - _________. "Impression preparations and the van gieson stain for negri bodies." Reprinted from the American Journal of Public Hygiene, February 1908. (Box 2)
  - Furtuna, M. "Etablissement de principes unifromes pour l'estimation de la reaction de la tuberculine et de la malleine. VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire a Budapest, 1905. (Box 2)
- G
  - Gage, Simon Henry. "The anti-coagulating action of the secretion of the buccal glands of the lampreys (petromyzon, lampetra and entosphenus)." Reprinted from Science, September 1927. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Apparatus and methods for micro-incineration." Reprinted from Stain Technology, January 1938. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Artificial daylight for the microscope." Reprinted from Science, October 1915. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The comparative physiology of respiration." Reprinted from The American Naturalist, October 1892. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Fat digestion, absorption and assimilation in man and animals as determined by the dark-field microscope, and a fat-soluble dye." Reprinted from the American Journal of Anatomy, Vol. 34, No.1, September 1924. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The Ferris-Blauvelt bill for direct primaries, 1911: Comparison with the Hinman-Green Bill of 1910." Reprinted from the Ithaca Daily Journal, May 25, 1911. (Box 2)
  - ________, Grant Sherman Hopkins and D.H. Udall. "The first faculty of the New York State Veterinary College." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, Vol. XXIV, No.2, April 1934. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The flower library of the New York State Veterinary College." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, Vol.XX, No.4, October 1930. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Glycogen in the nervous system of vertebrates." Reprinted from the Journal of Comparative Neurology, June 1917.. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The Hinman-Green bill for direct nominations: Comparison with the Meade-Philips Bill." Reprinted from the Ithaca Daily Journal, April 7, 1910. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Histology and methods of instruction." Reprinted from the Transactions of the Ninteenth Annual Meeting of the American Microscopical Society, August 1896. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The importance and the promise in the study of the domestic animals." Reprinted from the proceedings of the forty-eighth Annual Meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, August 1899. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Improvements in oil-sectioning with collodion." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the American Microscopical Society, Vol.XVII, 1895. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The introduction of photographic transparencies as lantern slides." Reprinted from the Journal of the Royal Society of Arts, January 1911. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Lampreys and their ways." Reprinted from The Scientific Monthly, May 1929. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The lampreys of New York State: Life history and economics." Reprinted from Biological Survey of the Oswego River System, Supplemental to Seventeenth Annual Report, New York State Conservation Department, 1927. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The life history of the toad." Teacher's leaflets for use in the public schools, prepared by the College of Agriculture, Cornell University, No.9, April 1898. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Life-history of the vermilion-spotted newt." Reprinted from the American Naturalist, December 1891. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Marker for indicating the position of objects or parts of objects in microscopical preparations." Proceedings of the American Microscopial Society, 1894. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Methods of decalcification in which the structural elements are preserved." Reprinted from the proceedings of the American Microscopical Society, Vol. XIV, 1892. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Modern dark-field microscopy and the history of its development." Reprinted from the Transactions of the American Microscopical Society, April 1920. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Notes on fibrin, oxyhaemoglobin crystals and the collodion method." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Society of Microscopists, 1891. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Notes on Historical methods including a brief consideration of the methods of pathlogical and vegetable histology." For the use of laboratory students in the anatomical department of the Cornell University, 1885-86. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Notes on the isolation of the tissue elements." Reprinted from the Transactions of the American Microscopical Society, 1897. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The origin and development of the projection microscope." Reprinted from the Transactions of the American Microscopical Society, June 1906. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Picric and chromic acid for the rapid preparation of tissues for classes in histology." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Society of Microscopists, 1890. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The presence of micro-particles in the blood and other body fluids." Reprinted from the Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, January 1921. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The processes of life revealed by the microscope; a plea for physiological histology." Reprinted from the Smithsonian Report for 1896, 1898 (Box 2)
  - ________. "The processes of life revealed by the microscope; a plea for physiological histology." Reprinted from the Transactions of the American Microscopical Society, Vol.XVII, 1895. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The projection microscope." Reprinted from The Microscope, 9th Edition, 1904. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The purpose of the New York State Science Teacher's Association and the work it hopes to accomplish." Reprinted from Science, March 19, 1897. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Recent developments in drawing by the aid of projection apparatus used on the house lighting system." Reprinted from the Transactions of the American Microscopical Society, Volume XXXI, 1912. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The relation of Ezra Cornell to the New York State Agriculture College at Ovid and to the People's College at Havana." Founder's Day Talk before the Cornell Club of Ithaca on the 117th anniversary of the birth of Ezra Cornell, January 11, 1924. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Relation of the ureters and the great veins in the cat." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of American Anatomists, 28-30 December 1898. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Retirement of Professor Burt Green Wilder." Reprinted from The Anatomical Record, July 1911. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Retirement of Professor John Henry Comstock." Reprinted from the Cornell Countryman, April 1914. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Sketch of the life of John Henry Comstock, Professor Emeritus of Entomology in Cornell University." Reprinted with the permission of the National Council of Boy Scouts of America, from Boy Scout Booklet, Insect Life, by J. Chester Bradley and E.L. Palmer, 1925. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Some apparatus for the microscopical laboratory." Reprinted from The Anatomical Record, June 1916. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Some apparatus to facilitate the work of the histological and embryological laboratory." Reprinted from the Journal of Applied Microscopy, Vol.1, No.7., July 1898 (Box 2)
  - ________. "Special oil-immersion objectives for dark-field microscopy." Reprinted from Science, Vol.LIV, No.1406, December 1921. (Box 2)
  - ________and Susanna Phelps Gage. "Staining and permanent preservation of histological elements isolated by means of caustic potash (KOH) or nitric acid (HNO^3)." Reprinted from Proceedings of American Society of Microscopists, 1889. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Susanna Phelps Gage." Reprinted from the Journal of Comparative Neurology, December 1916. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Theobald Smith: investigator and man, 1859-1934." Reprinted from Science, August 7th, 1936. (Box 2)
  - ________ and P.A. Fish. "The ultraparticles of the blood and chyle." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1921. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Veranus Alva Moore 1859-1931." Reprinted from the Journal of Bacteriology, July 1931. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Zymogen granules in the fishes." Reprinted from Transactions of the American Fisheries Society, Vol.72, 1942. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Zymogen granules of the pancreas in vertebrates." Reprinted from Transactions of the American Microscopical Society, Vol.LXIV, No.2, April 1942. (Box 2)
  - Gage, Susanna Phelps. "A three weeks' human embryo with especial reference to the brain and the nephric system." Reprinted from the American Journal of Anatomy, 15 September 1905. (Box 2)
  - Galloway, B.T. "Report on the experiments made in 1891 in the treatment of plant diseases." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 3, 1892. (Box 2)
  - Gardner, L. Pearl. "The response of cows to the same signal in different positions." Reprinted from the Journal of Comparative Medicine, April 1937. (Box 2)
  - Geschickter, Charles F. "Laboratory aids in surgery of the bones and joints." Reprinted from The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, May 1931. (Box 2)
  - Gibier, Paul. "Serumtheraphy in poisoning by the venom of snakes." Bulletin of the Pasteur Institute, 1897. (Box 2)
  - Gibson, H.B., S. Calvert and D.W. May. "Dietary studies at the Universityof Missouri in 1895 and data relating to bread and meat consumption in Missouri." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 31, 1896. (Box 2)
  - Gilbert, Ruth and Marion B. Coleman. "Recent cases of undulant fever in New York State." Reprinted from the Journal of Infectious Diseases, October 1928. (Box 2)
  - Gill, Theodore. "Note on the genus chonerhinus or xenopterus." Proceedings U.S. National Musuem, 1884. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Note on the genus hiatula of lacepee or tatoga of mitchill." Proceedings of U.S. National Musuem, 1884? (Box 2)
  - ________. "Notes on the tetraodontoida." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States National Musuem, 1892. (Box 2)
  - ________. "On the genus gnathanacanthus of bleeker." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States National Musuem, 1884? (Box 2)
  - Gilman, Herbert J. and E.L. Brunett. "Bacterium Abortus Infection in the Fowl II." Reprinted from the Report of the New York State Veterinary College for the Year 1930-31. (Box 2)
  - Givens, Amos J. "Prevention of nervous and mental diseases through extension of medical inspection of schools." Read at the Stamford Medical Society, January 1911. (Box 2)
  - Gochenour, William S., et al. "In fectious anemia (swamp fever). U.S. Department of Agriculture Farmers' Bulletin No 1819, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Gmelin, W. "Die aufsaugung, resorption." 1910. (Box 2)
  - Goldberg, Samuel A. "Changes in organs of thyroidectomised sheep and goats." Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology, Vol.XVII, June 1927. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Differential features between melanosis and melanosarcoma." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the New York State Veterinary Medical Society, 1920. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Effect of x-ray on experimental encephalitis in mice inoculated with the St. Louis Strain." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1935. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Epidermoid carcinoma in domesticated animals." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, October 1920. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The pathology of arthritis." Reprinted from American Journal of Clinical Pathology, Vol.14, No.1, January 1944. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The pathology of spavin." Reprinted from the Journal of Medical Research, Vol. XXXVIII, May 1918. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Primary splenic neoplasms." Reprinted from American Journal of Clinical Pathology, Vol. 10, No.10, October 1940. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The rationale of x-ray treatment in encephalitis lethargica." Reprinted from Radiology, Vol.XXII, No.6, June 1934. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The structural changes that occur in certain non-specific inflammations of joints." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University, 1914-1915. (Box 2)
  - Graham, J.R. and H.G. Wolf. "The emchanism of migraine headache and action of ergotamine tartrate. Gynergen Abstract Series No. 4, Sandoz Chemical Works, 1938. (Box 2)
  - Gray, John W. "Classification and treatment of chronic arthritis." Journal of the Medical Society of New Jersey, May 1935. (Box 2)
  - ________, Fendrick and Gowen. "Rheumatic fever and rheumatoid arthritis/ rheumatic fever and rheumatoid arthritis from the laboratory point of view." Texas State Journal of Medicine, July/ September 1932. (Box 2)
  - ______ and Cecil H. Gowen. "The role of the streptococcus in arthritis deformans." American Journal of the Medical Sciences, November 1931. (Box 2)
  - Graybill, H.W. and Theobald Smith. "Production of fatal blackheda in turkeys by feeding embryonated eggs of heterakis papillosa." Reprinted from the Jounral of Experimental Medicine, May 1920. (Box 2)
  - Greene, Carl H., Albert M. Snell and Waltman Walters, "Functional tests in the surgical diagnosis and treatment of diseases of the liver and bile ducts." Reprinted from The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, May 1931. (Box 2)
  - Greenough, Robert B. "Treatment of malignant diseases with radium and x-ray." Reprinted from Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, August 1929. (Box 2)
  - Gruber, Th. "Die Milch und deren Behandlung mit besondere Rucksicht auf die Reform des melkens, entsprechend den hyienishen anforderungen." VIII Internationaler Tierarzlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905. (Box 2)
  - Gruenberg, Benjamin C. "The chains of Prometheus." Reprinted from The Scientific Monthly, December 1927. (Box 2)
  - Guild, Harriet G. "The prognosis of acute glomerular nephritis in childhood." Reprinted form Bulletin of the Johns Hopkins Hospital, April 1931. (Box 2)
  - Guimaraes, Ugo Pinheiro, et al. "O 'kondrocurare' na anestesia por inhalacao." Reprinted from Brasileira de Cirurgia, 1948. (Box 2)
  - Gunsalus, I.C. et al. "The bacteriology of bull semen. II. The effect of Bacteria upon rapid tests for semen quality." Reprinted from Journal of Diary Science, May 1944. (Box 2)
- H
  - Hagan, W.A. "Age as a factor in susceptibility to Johne's disease." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1938, Vol.XXVIII, No.1. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The animal reservoirs of brucellosis." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, January 1937, Vol. XXVII, No.1. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Braken poisoning of cattle." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, July 1925. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The diagnosis of anthrax from putrefying animal tissues." Reprinted from The Journal of Bacteriology, Vol. V, No.4, July 1920. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Experimental bracken poisoning of cattle." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1927. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Evolucion de la virologia." Reprinted from the Boletin de la Oficina Sanitaria Panamericana, Vol. XLIII, No.5, November 1957. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Fat necrosis in cattle." Reprinted from the Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, September 1921. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Formation of peroxide by actinomyces necrophorus on exposure to air in relation to anaerobic plate cultures." Reprinted from The Journal of Infectious Diseases, October 1924, Vol. 35. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The gins method of demonstrating capsules of bacteria." Reprinted from Science, August 1927, Vol. LXVI, No. 1703. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The green coloration by certain streptococci on blood agar." Reprinted from The Journal of Infectious Diseases, Vol. 37, No.1, July 1925. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The green coloration by certain streptococci on blood agar plates." Reprinted from the 1925 Annual Report of the State Veterinary College. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The isolation of acid-fast bacteria from soil." Reprinted from The American Review of Tuberculosis, Vol.XXXVI, No.4, October 1937. (Box 2)
  - ________ and Harriet Mansfield Thomson. "Johne's Disease and its causative organism." Reprinted from the Transactions of the Twenty-seventh Annual Meeting of the National Tuberculosis Association, 1931. (Box 2)
  - ________ and A. Zeissig. "Johne's disease or paratuberculosis of cattle." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University for the year 1927-1928. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Johne's disease or paratuberculosis of cattle with a note on the disease in sheep." Reprinted from Symposium Series Vol.I of the American Association for the Advancement of Science. (Box 2)
  - ________ and A. Zeissig. "Johnin versus avian tuberculosis as a diagnostic agent for paratuberculosis (Johne's Disease) of cattle." Reprinted from Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, Vol.LXXIV, No.7, June 1929. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The lesions produced by the bacillus of Johne's disease in the peritoneal cavity of the guinea pig." Reprinted from Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, Vol. LXXVI, N.S.2, No.29, February 1930. (Box 2)
  - ________. "Nomenclature of pathogenic bacteria." Reprinted from Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, Vol.LXXII, N.S.25, No.3, December 1927. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The no-visible-lesion case problem in tuberculosis eradication." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States Live Stock Sanitary Association, 1941. (Box 2)
  - ________. "The no-visible-lesion case problem in tuberculosis eradication." Reprinted from the Cornell Veterinarian, April 1931. (Box 2)